(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T13:52:25.087912",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あー、始まりましたー！
Ah, it's starting!
いぇーい！
Yay!
いろはにほへと あやふみに 恋情詩歌リリース記念3Dコラボ配信！
"Renjou Shiika" release commemoration 3D collaboration stream!
いぇーい！いぇーい！いぇーい！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
あれ、久しぶりじゃん！お久しぶり！
Huh, long time no see! Welcome back!
お久しぶりだけど、どうしたキャラ？
It's been a while, but what's with that persona?
なんかいつもと違う、キャラどうしちゃったの？
You look different from usual, what happened to your character?
うちは！うちだよ、うちうち！狼みおだよ！あれ、どうした？
It's me! It's me, me! Ookami Mio! Huh, what's wrong?
え、ちょっとこの1週間の間にちょっと見失ってきた、自分のこと…
Wait, in just this one week, I've kinda lost sight of who I am...
なになになに？見失わないでよ！やめてよ！
What, what, what? Don't lose sight! Stop it!
1週間で、もっと自己紹介してましょ、じゃあ！
Let's do a self-introduction for a bit, then!
思い出して！もっと元気あったよ！
Remember! You had more energy!
うちはよ！うちうち！おおかみみおだよ！
It's me! Me, me! Ookami Mio!
あれ？もっとのぶとかった気がしたっけ？もっと可愛かった気がする…！
Huh? Did I sound deeper before? I feel like I was cuter...!
えい、えい、えい！でも、おかえりお久しぶり！おかえりだよー！
Ei, ei, ei! But welcome back, long time no see! Welcome back!
霊能神…それ、こんな感じだったっけ？
Reinou Kami... Was it really like this?
よも3Dの企画久しぶりだから、よもやっ得うか？ええ、じゃあいいですか？
Since it's been a while for Ayame's 3D planning, shall we do Ayame's too? Eh, is that okay?
みんな、こんなきりっ…！こんなきり、あやめです！
Everyone, like this kiri...! Like this kiri, I'm Ayame!
生ナキリだ！なんかちょっと怪しい、怪しいですけど…
It's live Nakiri! It sounds a bit sketchy, sketchy, but...
なんだろ、こんなこと…久しぶりに聞いたな、生ナキリだ！
What is this... I haven't heard that in a while, live Nakiri!
そしてそして、白上フブキです！いつものフブキだよ！
And then, I'm Shirakami Fubuki! It's the usual Fubuki!
いつもの通りだ！いつもの通りでいいんですよ！
It's the usual way! The usual way is fine!
本日はですね、連情詩歌のリリースを記念しまして、3D配信です！
Today, to commemorate the release of "Renjou Shiika", we are holding a 3D stream!
せっかく3人で集まったので、様々な企画に挑戦していきたいと思います！
Since the three of us managed to gather, we want to take on various challenges!
なんやらは、罰ゲームもあるということで…罰ゲームは大丈夫ですよ、もう！
There's also punishment games... Punishment games are fine, really!
あ ちょっと、
Ah, let's see.
待って、いや、
Wait, no.
やばい、やばい。
Yabai, yabai.
ちょっと生のりたとこに浸ってたからさ。
It was sitting right in the raw footage area.
地獄をね、思い出していくね。
We'll remember the hell one by one, yeah.
はい、思い出していきましょ。
Right, remembering them.
あんまり思い出したくないけどね。
Well, I don't really want to remember.
まあ、できれば回避していきたいとこです。
Well, if we can, we want to dodge it.
はい。
Yeah.
配信の最後にはですね、
And at the end of the stream,
ホロライブミュージックのTwitterにて募集しました、
we solicited on Hololive Music's Twitter!
短歌のグランプリを遂に発表させていただきますので、お楽しみにー！
The tanka grand prix will finally be announced, so look forward to it!
いえーい！何が選ばれるんでしょ？
Yay! What will be chosen?
そう、何が選ばれるのか！
Yeah, what will be chosen?
ねえ、なんか応募数半端なかったらしいので、
You know, the submissions were incredible,
ちょっとね、後ほどご紹介したいと思います。
we'll introduce some of them later.
はいす。
Yes.
すんにも今回ですね、連続リリース記念ということで、
And this time is the continuous release commemoration,
皆さんちゃんと聴いてくれましたか？
did everyone listen to it properly?
お！ちゃんと聴いてましたか、皆さん。
Oh! Did you listen?
聴いてますか？
Are you listening?
聴いててますか？
Did you listen?
聴きましたか？どうですか？
Did you listen? How is it?
のって、のって、のって。はー、聴いたよって来たんで、の、の、聴いた、聴いた、の、の、の、の、
"No, no, no." "Ah, I listened," they say. "No, no, no, no."
の、の、の、の、の、あ、の、がいっぱいある、いっぱいある、いっぱいある。毎日聴いてるだって。
Ah, there are lots of "no"s. Lots of "no"s. Lots of "no"s. "I listen every day," they say.
お！
Oh!
毎日聴いてる。
Oh, listening every day.
やい！
Yay!
や、みんな言ってる、聴いてるって。
Yeah, everyone says they're listening.
よかったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay, thank you!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
あやめちゃんがなんか特に連続リリース好きっていうの。
Ayame-chan, you especially like continuous releases, right?
いや、そうなんですよ。
Yeah, that's right.
連続リリースが結構トップで好きですかね。
Continuous releases are pretty top, I love them.
ちょっと鬼の曲ね、はい。
You know, ogre songs, yeah.
ねえ、みんなぜひ聴いてください。
Well, everyone, please listen to it.
まだの人もね、聴いてください。
New people, please listen to it.
はい。ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
Yes, please.
それでは、早速企画していきましょうか！
Well then, let's start the project!
お、何が来るんだ？
What will it be?
いや、本日最初の企画は、
Well, today's first project is...
ホロライブ体対決ー！
Hololive Body Battle!
いえーい！いえいえいえ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
わっしょい、わっしょい、わっしょいわっしょい！
Washoi, washoi, washoi, washoi!
で、短歌からですね、これまで募集しました短歌、
Now then, from the tanka we solicited,
なんと、5,000首以上いただいたんですよ！
なんと、5,0003以上いただいたんですよ！
そうなんです！え、5,000首ってすごくない？
So many! Wait, 5,000? That's amazing!
最後は5,000首の中のグランプリなのでね。
The end is the Grand Prix out of 5,000.
やばい！凝縮されますのでね。
Amazing! It's going to be so condensed!
多すぎる！
Too many!
よくその数くぐり抜けてきた。
You pushed through that number.
そうそう、それがね、一番最後に発表されますけれども。
Right, those will be announced last.
ま、今回はその募集したね、あの短歌を使って、
So, using the tanka we solicited,
かるたゲームもしていこうと思います。
we're going to play a karuta game!
はい。でね、募集した中から2段、第2弾、第3弾で、あの募集した上ノ句、かみのくを使って、かるたに挑戦していきます。
Yes, and from the submissions, we'll use the upper phrases of the 2nd and 3rd tiers to challenge the karuta!
これからですね、我々3人の中で読み手と取り手に分かれようと思います。
From now on, the three of us will be split into readers and card-takers.
はいはいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
ちなみにね、普段には我々がね、それぞれ考えた下ノ句書いてありますよね。
By the way, normally we each thought of lower phrases, right?
せせせーのよよよとかありましたけど。
The "yoyoyo" of "sesese", etc.
あったねー！
Ah, that's right!
なので、そうそう。読み手が読んだ上ノ句がどの下ノ句に対応したものかっていうのをね、見つけていこうと思います。
So, we're going to figure out which lower phrase the reader's upper phrase corresponds to.
なるほどね。
I see.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
ちゃんと覚えてたりしますか？なんか見たことあるな、この短歌とかね。
Do you remember them? Like, "Oh, I've seen this tanka before."
まあまあまあまあ。
Well,まあまあまあまあ。
私らがね、作ったから、ね、チェックね、私たちもね。
Well, we made them, so we'll check, right?
でね、最初のじゃあかるた、どうしましょうか？読み手。
So, for the first karuta, what should we do? Reader?
じゃあ最初、どうしようかな、じゃあ最初は。
Then first, shall we do the first?
読み手、はい。
Reader, yes.
がんばります。ちなみに、えっと、
And, um,
募集したやつ、あ、第2弾の、第3弾のの考えた下ノ句を、おさらい、
the ones we solicited, the 2nd and 3rd tier lower phrases we thought of.
あ、そうだよ、下ノ句をおさらい。そうそうそう。みんなちょっと覚えてるかどうかって。
Ah, that's right, let's review the lower phrases. We remember them, right?
我々の、はい、第2弾、第3弾なんで考えた下ノ句、おさらいです。こんな感じでした。
Our, yes, the lower phrases we thought of for the 2nd and 3rd tiers, let's review them. Something like this.
お！
Oh!
おー！
なんかすごい真面目な顔してるけどもさ。
You look so serious, though.
ちょっと、なんだ、真ん中の、真ん中の。
Wait, what about the middle one?
真ん中の人ちょっとすごい決めた顔で「よ、よ、よ」とか言ってんの、ちょっと。
The person in the middle has such a determined face, going "Yo, yo, yo!"
ね。ちょっと、なんか、気合入ってるのね。
Right, right.
ちょっと1人ずつ読んでいきますか。白上が、え、最高級のあぶらあげなり、と
Let's read them one by one. Fubuki, go ahead.
もっちゃもっちゃきつねのうどん、でした。はい。食べ物ですね。ええ。
"Moccha moccha kitsune no udon." That's what it was.
あやめのがね、せっせっせーのよ、よ、よ。
Ayame's was "Sesse sesse no yo yo yo!"
え、今日ってかわいいんだよがよ、よ、よ。発し、そう、夏なんだよな、なんか。
"Kyootte kawaiiyonda yo ga yo yo!" Oh, wait, it's "natsunanoka" somewhere.
みおは？はい。
Mio's? Yes.
え、ミオフアの森もいとさんざめく。そして、こわやこわやとみお泣きうなる、ですね。
"Miofa no mori mo ito sanzameku" and "Kowaya kowaya to mio naki unaru" is it?
こんな感じでしたね。
That sort of thing?
ま、これが下ノ句としてね、あの、かるたにありますのでね。はいはい。一体ね、どんな感じで繋がるのか皆さん。
So these are the lower phrases for the karuta, so let's see how they connect.
ぜひぜひ皆さんね、予想していただいて、お楽しみだ。
Look forward to it, everyone!
はい。
Yes.
では、始めていきましょうか！
Then let's get started!
やりやる！
Let's do it!
じゃあ最初じゃあ白上が読んで、2人がじゃあ下ノ句を探す係ということで。オッケー！
Okay, first Shirakami will read, and the two of us will search for the lower phrase. Okay!
はいはいはい。
Yes!
じゃあ次は、次どうする？次。
Wait, what about the next one?
次読むのどうする？
Who reads next? How should we do it?
じゃあ、みおを、読みましょうか。オッケー。じゃあ最後はあやめ。
Well, let Mio read. Okay, Mio. And then Ayame.
じゃあ最初はじゃあ、読みま。
First is, let's read.
あやめが読んじゃいましょう。じゃあ2人が、はい。
Ayame will read, and the two of us will...
見つけてもらって。
Find it, morote.
よしよしよしよし。
Yosh, yosh, yosh.
ね、なんかあの、お正月にもこんなかるたをやりましたけども。
We did this karuta for New Year's too, but...
ね、やりましたね！
Yeah, we did!
はい。
Yes.
ちょっとあやふみでは初めてですね。
This is the first time for Ayafumi, right?
そうですね。初めてだ。
That's right, it's the first time.
そう、特殊なカメラを用いて、なんと床にかるたが現れるということで、
Using a special camera, karuta appears on the floor.
はい！
Yay!
ねぇねぇ、カメラもたまに…あ、はい！
Hey, hey, the camera is occasionally... oh, yes!
おっ、オッケー、準備できましたかね？
Oh, okay, are you ready?
はい、準備完了しました。
Yes, we're all set.
でもスタートしちゃって大丈夫ですかね？
Is it okay to just start?
一体どんな感じかつうのを、じゃあちょっと画面切り替えて見せてもらってもよろしいですかね？
Can you switch screens and show us what it's like?
どうしますか？
How should we do it?
はいはい。
Sure, sure.
おー、こんな感じですね、はい！
Oh, something like this, yes!
こんな感じで、あやめちゃん視点、ちゃんとあやめちゃんですか？
Like this. Ayame-chan's viewpoint... is this really Ayame-chan's?
あ、よーが、あ、よーふり……
Oh, Yo-ga... Oh, Yo-fu...
で、みお視点は、ちゃんとみおですか？
And Mio's viewpoint... is this really Mio's?
はい、ブンブンブンブン！
Yes, zoom zoom zoom zoom!
ま、こんな感じで、床にね、下野君がありまして、白上がいまから読む神野君。さあ、どれが繋がるかっていうのをね、考えてください。
So like this, there are Shimono cards on the floor, and Shirakami will read Kamino cards. So please think about which ones connect.
こうやってちょっとね、遠めで見てね、はい。では、いいですか？
You look at it from a distance like this. Alright, is everyone ready?
はい、できますよ。
Yes, we're ready.
それでは、かるた対決、スタート！
Then, the karuta battle, start!
まず、神野君をまず聞いていただきます。はい。
First, please listen to Kamino. Yes.
よろしくお願いします。
Please.
チェケラッチョ！DJ☆Joyo 意気揚々々！
Check it out! DJ Joyo, full of spirit!
えー、それではに繋がる下野君を、カメラ内に収めてください！
Eh, please capture the matching Shimono card within the camera!
ええ、これま、でも、あ、これ完全にあやめ町のやつじゃん！これじゃないですか？どうですか？ちょっと、チェケラッチョDJ☆Joyo 意気揚々々！
Eh, wait, this is completely Ayame's! Isn't this it? What do you think? Check it out, DJ Joyo, full of spirit!
まあ、でもじゃあうちわこっちかな？こっちかな？
Well, then is Uchi-wa this way? Or this way?
はーはーはーはー、これなんじゃないかな。なるほど。こちらはハンドルネーム「ジルにゃん」のしっぽさんから送られたものです。
Ha ha ha, isn't this it? I see. This is sent from handle name "Jirunyan's Tail".
あやめちゃんが今日は、京都で、可愛いよがよーよ……可愛いよがよーよーで、みおがせーせーせーのよーよーよーですね。
Ayame is today in Kyoto, cute yo-ga yo-yo... cute yo-ga yo-yo-yo, and Mio is se-se-se-no yo-yo-yo.
では、こちら正解は、京都で可愛いよがよーよーでしたー！やったー！
So, the correct answer here was "Cute in Kyoto, yo-ga yo-yo"! Yay!
そっちだったかー！というこで、あやめちゃんにここでポイントが入ります！
It was that one! So Ayame gets a point here!
やったー！あやめちゃん1ポイントです。
Yay! Ayame has 1 point.
まあでもじゃあうちわはだよ。やだよ。というでジルにゃんのしっぽから送られてきたものですね、ありがとうございます。
Well, but I don't want to. So it was sent from Jirunyan's Tail, thank you very much.
お家でお留守番しております。お留守番がおります。
I'm staying home. Staying home.
じゃあ続いて第2問もいきましょうか。はい、第2問もいきます。
Well then let's go to the second question. Yes, let's go to the second question.
神野君、今いくぞ！
Kamino, going now!
怖がる仲間に駆け付くも……
Rushing to scared companions...
あーー！
Ahhh!
こちらはハンドルネーム「ネコパス」さんからですね。今いくぞ、怖がる仲間に駆け付くも……さあ、その下野君なんでしょう！
This is from handle name "Nekopasu". Rushing to scared companions... Now, what could that Shimono be!
え、これは、これは、さあさあさあ、どっちですかね？こっちかな？
Eh, this is, well, which one is it? Is it this one?
はあ、みおの君だと思ってるんですかね、2人とも。あ、みおちゃんの、かなと思うんですけど、なるほど。こちらでしょうか。
Huh, you think it's Mio's card, both of you. Ah, I think it's Mio-chan's, I see. Is it this one?
あ、あやめちゃん二人読めますか？
Ah, Ayame, can both of you read it?
え、みおファンの森も、意図散々めく。みおファンの森も意図散々めく。みおは？
Eh, Mio fan's forest is also torn to pieces. Mio's is?
え、こわやこわやとみお鳴きうなる。
Eh, crying out in fear, Mio howls.
はい、じゃあ正解は！
Yes, then the correct answer is!
こわやこわやとみお鳴きうなりました！
Crying out in fear, Mio howled!
やったーー！引けましたー！ということで、みおちゃん1ポイント入りました！
Yay! I pulled it! So Mio gets 1 point!
では、続いていきますよ。はい、続いて……
Well then, moving on. Yes, moving on...
あなたとね、食べるご飯が大好きです……あれ？
Eating meals with you is my favorite... Huh?
こちらはハンドルネーム「だんちょー」さんからいただきました。
This was received from handle name "Dancho".
あなたとね、食べるご飯が大好きです。
Eating meals with you is my favorite.
あれ？ちょっと待ってね。あなたとね、食べるご飯が大好きです。
Huh? Wait a minute. Eating meals with you is my favorite.
え、どっちのカードにしようかな、じゃあ。
Eh, which card should I choose then?
お、決めました！あ、じゃああやめちゃんそれを読んでもらっていいですか？
Oh, decided! Ayame, could you read that?
もっちゃもっちゃの、ん？もっちゃもっちゃキツネのうどん。
Mocchamoccha kitsune no udon.
みおは、最高級のあぶらあげなり。
Mio's is top-tier fried tofu.
さあ、正解は！
Now, the correct answer is!
もっちゃもっちゃキツネのうどん！あ、残念！あぶらあげじゃない。
Mocchamoccha kitsune no udon! Ah, too bad! It's not fried tofu.
もっちゃもっちゃキツネのうどんでした！あやめちゃんにも1ポイント入ります！やったー！ありがとうざいます！
It was mocchamoccha kitsune no udon! Ayame gets 1 point too! Yay! Thank you!
じゃあ続いて、じゃあ読み手交代しましょうか。
Then next, let's switch readers.
じゃあみおと、あ、私が読む。
Then Mio and... Ah, I will read.
じゃあ、ふぶきちゃんに、交代、あ、じゃあふぶきカメラになりますね。
Then Fubuki, switching... Ah, then it becomes Fubuki camera.
では、変わらずやりますよ。よし、見つけられるぜ。
Well, we'll keep doing it. Alright, I'll find it.
では、参ります。よろしいですか、お二人とも。お願いします！
Then, here we go. Is that okay, you two? Please!
それでは読ませていただきます。
Then I will read it.
えー、ハンドルネーム「ルナール」さんからの句です。
Eh, this is a verse from handle name "Renard".
あぶらあげ、七味いっぱい薬味ねぎ。
Fried tofu, lots of shichimi, yakumi negi.
あぶらあげ七味いっぱい薬味ねぎ。え、まじ？これですか？
Fried tofu, lots of shichimi, yakumi negi. Eh, seriously? Is this it?
これ？お、さらに最高級の可能性がある。
This? Oh, there's a possibility of it being even higher quality.
ああ、確かに。え、そっちあるな。
Ah, true. Eh, that one might be it.
じゃあね、あやめのほうを読んでください。
Now then, please read Ayame's card.
おっ、またしても、もっちゃもっちゃ絆のうどん！
Oh, once again, it's "Mocchamoccha Kizuna's Udon!"
最高級の油揚げなり。
And "The highest grade fried tofu."
おお、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
汁飲み干したら辛いやつかもしれない。
If you drink all the broth, it might be spicy.
正解は……もっちゃもっちゃ絆のうどん！
The correct answer is... "Mocchamoccha Kizuna's Udon!"
やったー！
Yay!
絆のうどんのほうだったか！辛い油揚げじゃなかったかー！ポイント重ねていく！
It was Kizuna's Udon! It wasn't the spicy fried tofu! Accumulating points!
では、お次の番です。ほい。
Now, it's the next person's turn. Here.
あ、ヒグさんからいただいた。
Ah, received from Higu-san.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
鬼だけど……
Though a demon...
鬼だけど、悪さはしないアイドルさ。
Though a demon, I do no evil, an idol.
せっせっせーの、Yo! Yo! Yo!
Sesseesse, Yo! Yo! Yo!
あーなるほどね、悪さはしないけどせっせっせーはすりよっと。
Ah, I see, no evil, but you do sesseesse.
あやめのは……今日とってもかわいいんだYo! Yo! Yo!
Ayame's is... Today I'm super cute, Yo! Yo! Yo!
せっせっせーのYo! Yo! Yo!でしたー！
It was "Sesseesse-no Yo! Yo! Yo!"!
ではお次の問題いきます。
Now, let's move on to the next question.
てぇてぇな見守るフブキ、ハーモニカ……
Precious watching over Fubuki, harmonica...
見守るフブキ、ハーモニカ……
Watching over Fubuki, harmonica...
ミオファの森も、いとさんざめく。
Even Miofa's forest bustles lovingly.
こわや、こわやと、ミオ鳴きうなる。
How frightening, how frightening, Mio cries and howls.
正解は、こわや、こわやとミオ鳴きうなるでしたー！
The correct answer was "How frightening, how frightening, Mio cries and howls"!
何が来るかな？ハンドルネーム、カオスK.U.さんからいただきました。
What will come? Handle name, received from Chaos K.U.-san.
始まるよ、陽気に響くウクレレに……
It begins, to the cheerful sounding ukulele...
始まるよ、陽気に響くウクレレに、もっちゃもっちゃのきつねうどん。
It begins, to the cheerful sounding ukulele, Mocchamoccha's kitsune udon.
始まるよ、陽気に響くウクレレに、ミオファの森もいとさんざめく。
It begins, to the cheerful sounding ukulele, even Miofa's forest bustles lovingly.
始まるよ 陽気に響く ウクレレに ミオファの森も いとさんざめく。
ハンドルネーム、8月の朝霧さんからいただきました。
Handle name, received from Asagiri of August-san.
愛込めて、あの（こ）に捧ぐ、この一杯。
Pouring love into this cup dedicated to that fox.
画面に似ている鳥… 狐の…
A bird resembling a screen... A fox's...
今度こそこれでは！
This time for sure!
さあさあさあ、あのこに…？
Come on, come on, to that child...?
探す、この一杯！
Search for this cup!
この一杯ときたら、せっせっせーの…
When it's this cup, it's "Sesesse-no..."
あれ？これでも…これなんか？…あ、そっか、こっちか！
Huh? Is this it? Or is this it? Oh right, this way!
なるほど、勢いありましたか？
I see, was there momentum?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあちょっとみおさんから読んでもらいましょうか。
Then let's have Mio-san read it.
あの子に捧ぐこの一杯 せっせっせーの よーよーよー！
A cup dedicated to that child, sesesse-no yo-yo-yo!
なるほど、これ！
I see, this!
なるほどね。
I see.
はい、一杯を勢いで捧げていくと。
Yes, dedicating a cup with momentum.
なるほど。
I see.
はい、じゃあフブキさん。 あの子に捧ぐこの一杯、もっちもっち狐のうどんで。
"A cup dedicated to that child, Mocchi-mocchi fox udon."
はい！ いや、これこそ。
Yes! No, this is it.
これ、まあ、まあ、まあ、まあ、じゃあ正解いきましょうか。
Let's go with the correct answer.
ほい！
Here!
読もね、一杯で数えたりします。
We count in cups when reading.
ねーそうですね。絶対そうじゃないですか！
Right, exactly. Isn't that totally it?
なんかおかしくなってるけどなんかすか？
It feels a bit weird though, what is it?
じゃあ正解いきましょう。
Well then, let's go to the correct answer.
えー、愛込めて、あのこに捧ぐ、この一杯。もっちもっち狐のうどんでしたー！
"With love, dedicating to that child, this cup. Mocchi-mocchi fox udon!"
フブキちゃん正解でーす！
Fubuki-chan is correct!
さすがにね、あやめを一杯って数えなか、いかじゃないもんね。
Naturally, you wouldn't count Ayame as "one cup", right?
いかは一杯って数えますけど。いかを一杯って数えられたらちょっとね、身悶えね。
If squid were counted as "pai", you'd writhe in agony.
おいしく…おいしく、もっちもっちしましょーね。
Let's make it delicious... deliciously chewy.
じゃあね、最後の問題いきましょうか！いぇーい！
Well then, let's go to the final question! Yay!
じゃあいきますよ。ハンドルネーム網揚げさんからいただきました！ありがとうございますー！
Received from handle name Amia-san! Thank you!
えー、余は何もしーとらんけど、まあいっか！
"I haven't done anything, but oh well!"
その続きをですね。え、じゃあこっちだな？
The continuation of that. Eh, so it's this one?
はい。え？これは、果たしてどれになるんでしょうか。
Yes. Eh? Which one will this turn out to be?
これ、どれにするんだろう。決まりましたか？はい！
I wonder which one this is. Have you decided? Yes!
どっちだ？これは、どっちでもいいよね。どっちでもいいじゃないかなーって思いますけども。
Which one? Either is fine. I think either is fine, though.
ねえ。じゃあ、どちらになるんでしょうか。正解を発表させていただきます！はい！
Well then, which one will it be? We will announce the correct answer! Yes!
余は何もしーとらんけど、まあいっか！今日って可愛いよね、余がYo! Yo! Yo! よーし！
"I haven't done anything, but oh well! Today is so cute, I'm Yo! Yo! Yo!" Yay!
みおちゃん正解でーす！よかったー！
Mio-chan is correct! Yay!
せっせっせーじゃなかったか！
It wasn't "sesesse-no"!
やでんこれどっちでもね、あやめちゃんじゃないかって感じでしたけども。
Though with this, either way it felt like it could be Ayame-chan, but...
なにも聞いてないけどせっせっせーしちゃう。本当になにも聞いてないんでしょうね。
Even though I heard nothing, I go "sesesse-no". You really weren't listening.
ということで、問題は以上になります。ありがとーございましたー！
With that, the questions are concluded. Thank you very much!
結構得点偏ったきも…,s:
The scores felt a bit lopsided...
なんか、ね。結構バラバラだぞ、これ。
Kind of, yeah. They're pretty scattered, this.
うん、バラバラになったんじゃないでしょうか。
Yeah, they became pretty scattered, didn't they?
今回は、はてさて、えっとね、うーんさん集計大丈夫でしょうかね？
This time, let's see, uhm, U-e-san, is the tallying alright?
どうですか？受けてます、集計の方。
How is it? Are they taking care of the tallying?
しばらくお待ちくださいということで、今んとこ集計してくれているらしいです。
Please wait a moment, it seems they are currently tallying.
はい。いや、かるた楽しいね、あれね。
Yes. Karuta is fun, you know.
壁抜けしちゃった！壁抜けしちゃったよ、みおちゃん！
She clipped through the wall! Mio-chan clipped through the wall!
みおちゃん！あれ、みおちゃん！？
Mio-chan! Huh, Mio-chan!?
わー！みおちゃん、ついに木だけで無く木の柱にまでハマっちゃった！
Whoa! Mio-chan finally got stuck even in the wooden pillar!
たまに津々浦々道場にされてしまうけどな。
Though it occasionally gets turned into a Tsumu-Ura-Ura dojo.
いやでもね、あの風真殿が新しい道場を開いてくれたからね。
Well, but you know, Kazama-dono opened a new dojo for us.
人、ここに津々浦々道場はなくなるはずだ！
People, the Tsumu-Ura-Ura dojo here should disappear!
津々浦々道場移動かっちゅー。
Moving the Tsumu-Ura-Ura dojo.
場所移動！
Location move!
お、ということで点数がまとまったらしいのでいきましょうか。
Oh, it seems the scores have been tallied, so let's go.
結果発表です！結果は、こちらー！
Result announcement! The results are here!
お？白上4点、あやめちゃんに点、あっ、3点、みおに点…あっ、3点、みおに点とゆーことで！
Shirakami 4 points, Ayame-chan 3 points, Mio 3 points, so!
白上がいんとこ1位ですね！いえーい！
Shirakami is currently in 1st place! Yay!
あれ？みおさん？あらららら。
Huh? Mio-san? Oh my, oh my.
でも綺麗にみおさんに…ねえ、みおさんになってますね、はいはい。
But it neatly became Mio-san... right, it became Mio-san, yes yes.
フブキの1点くれればちょうど…ちょうど…！
If you give me 1 point from Fubuki, it's just right... just right!
いやだめです！だめです！だめです！
No way! No, no, no!
あげるわけない！ちょっと久しぶりの配信だからってあげませんよ！
No way I'm giving it! Don't give it just because it's been a while!
そんな甘くないですよねー。
It's not that sweet, huh.
忖度はだめらしいですね。忖度はだめですか。
Favouritism apparently isn't allowed. Favouritism isn't allowed?
忖度はだめですね。そうですね。
Favouritism is no good. That's right.
ということで、いや、楽しかったですね、かるたね。
With that, man, karuta was fun.
もっと遊びたかったですね、かるた。
I wanted to play more karuta.
もっと難しくてもよかったかも。
Maybe it could have been even harder.
あー、確かに！もっと全然難しくてもね。まだなんかかるたも遊びたいですね。やりたいね。
I still want to play karuta. I want to play.
ということで以上、いろはにかるた対決でした！
With that, that was the Irohani Karuta showdown!
いぇーい！いぇーい！
Yay! Yay!
はい、それでは次の企画もいっちゃいましょうか！いっちゃおう！
Yes, well then, let's go to the next project! Let's go!
まだね、これだけじゃありませんからね。何が来るんでしょうか。
There's more than just this, you know. What could be coming?
と、その前にですね、次の企画はちょっとね、激しく激しくなるので、場所を移動しましょう！
And before that, the next project gets a bit intense, so let's move!
おお！おー！いけますぞ、レッツゴー！
Whoa! Oh! We can do it, let's go!
しっぽなしきり忍者、しっぽなしきり忍者です。お出口左側です。
I'm a Nakiri Ninja with no tail. Doors will open on the left.
あの、乗ります！乗せてください！
Um, I'm getting on! Please let me on!
悪い波を、この電車二人をなんだ。お出口閉まりまーす。
What are these two on this train braving the rough waves... Doors closing.
しゅー、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、乗せてくださーい！しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっぱーつ！なんだけど、引き返しまーす！
Choo, choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, please let me on! Choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, departing! Just kidding, heading back!
はあ、はあ、はあ……
Pant, pant, pant...
ここどこ？今日こそ小さな切り株……。
Where is this? Today's the day for the small tree stump...
本当にいるの？
Are they really here?
妖怪90%の確率でこの神社に潜んでるんだ！
There's a 90% chance yokai are lurking in this shrine!
本当に土の中にいるんか？土の中にいるらしいんだよ！
Are they really in the dirt? They apparently live in the dirt!
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、じゃあちょっと触るか。掘ってくれ、掘ってくれ！
Wait, wait, then let's touch it a bit. Dig, dig!
ここ掘れニャンニャン。ニャンニャンにょん。
Dig here, meow meow. Meow meow nyon.
え、本当かな？これいないな。
Huh, I wonder. Guess they're not here.
よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ。
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
これもしや、小さいのき！
Could this be the small Noki?!
え！？これだこれだ、可愛い！
Eh?! This is it, this is it, so cute!
よしよしよし、やったね！やったよー！
There, there, we did it! We did it!
おいおい、これ持って帰ろ。よし、これ持って帰ろ。
Hey, hey, let's take this home. Alright, let's take this home.
妖怪退散、妖怪退散！うわーー！
Yokai exorcism, yokai exorcism! Whoaーー!
いない！いない！
Not here! Not here!
よー！しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、乗せてくださーい！
Yo! Choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, please let me on!
しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっしゅっぽっぽ、しゅっぱーつ！
Choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, choo-choo-train, departing!
きききき、きききき、きききき……ききききき！
Kiki-kiki, kiki-kiki, kiki-kiki... kiki-kiki-ki!
早起きできたよ！早起きができました！やったー！
I woke up early! I was able to wake up early! Yay!
みんな可愛い！いぇーい！
Everyone is so cute! Yay!
久しぶりのアイドル衣装ですね。
It's been a while since our idol outfits.
本当だねー！
That's right!
はい！それでは次の企画に行きましょうか！
Yes! Now then, let's move on to the next segment!
こちらの企画は、曲？曲？曲？あ、これ企画企画！企画展、次の企画は！いろはにダンスチャレンジ！いぇーい！
This segment is... song? song? song? Ah, this is a project! Project exhibition, the next project is! Irohani Dance Challenge! Yay!
ダンスチャレンジ、はい、ダンスチャレンジなんですけども、私忘れてたんですけども、本日のハッシュタグはこちらです！
Dance challenge, yes, it's a dance challenge, but I forgot, today's hashtag is right here!
ハッシュタグいろはにコラボでぜひ呟いてください！これです、これです、これです、これです、お願いします！
Please tweet with the hashtag #IrohaniCollab! This is it, this is it, please do!
はい！ということでいろはにダンスチャレンジなんですけども、ここからみんなでですね、ポーズキミヨリと、レんじょうシイカのサビ部分のダンスを踊ります！
Yes! So, it's the Irohani Dance Challenge, and from here everyone will dance the chorus part of "Pose Kimiyori" and "Renjou Shiika"!
え？覚えてますよね、もちろん！え？え？ま、ま、ま、ただし、それが、どっちが流れるかはランダムです！
Eh? You remember it, of course! Eh? Eh? Well, well, well, however, which one plays will be random!
ランダムです！だんだん曲のスピードがアップしてきます！えー！？しかも、サビダッシュ？そう、サビダッシュ、急に言われたらちょっとね難しいじゃん。うまく踊れるかちょっと心配だな。
Random! The song speed gradually increases! Eh?! Moreover, chorus dash? Yes, chorus dash, if suddenly told it's a bit difficult. I'm a bit worried if we can dance well.
心配ですか？心配です。まあこれはですね、曲が速くなっても、正しくダンスは踊れるやろという……えー！？それをね、みんなでチャレンジしていきたいと思います。
Worried? Worried. Well, even if the song gets faster, you can still dance properly... Eh?! We want to challenge this together with everyone.
なんかですね、1.1倍から1.5倍まであるらしいんですけども、中には2倍に合わしてたので、2倍ちょっと怖いですね。5倍とかあったらどうしよう。
It seems there are speeds from 1.1x to 1.5x, and some were set to 2x, so 2x is a bit scary. What if there's 5x?
削っちゃいましょう！け、削っちゃいましょう！せっかくの痙攣にならないように頑張りたいと思います。ちゃんと踊れてたかは運営さんが判断してくれるそうです、マリエちゃんたちから。なるほど！なるほど、オッケーです。
Let's cut it! Let's cut it! We want to do our best not to get muscle spasms. Management will judge if we danced properly, Marie-chan and others. I see! I see, okay.
ではですね、まず通常スピードの「ポーズキミヨリ」と「レんじょうシイカ」のサビのダンスを確認して、行きたいと思います！ちょっと確認したいです。場所、場所、こっちなの？場所ね、場所どこだったっけ？まあとりあえず先見ちゃいましょうかね。ではまず「ポーズキミヨリ」のダンス、こちらです！
Now, first let's check and go over the chorus dance of "Pose Kimiyori" and "Renjou Shiika" at normal speed! I want to check a bit. Where is the location? Is it this way? Where was the location again? Well, let's watch first. First, here is the dance for "Pose Kimiyori"!
森の中のサーカスの君はそのピエロで いつも踊ってみせて皆を笑わせようとする
You're a clown in a forest circus, always playing the fool and making everyone laugh
どんな悲しいときも笑って 皆を笑わせようとする
You smile no matter how sad you are, trying to make everyone laugh
本当はとても気にしている そのヘンテコな赤い鼻も からかわれても知らんぷり
Truthfully, it bothers you so much, that strange red nose, pretending not to care even when mocked
踊って転んで笑ってたね つめづいたから涙が出るのが普通なんだよ
Dancing, falling, and laughing, it's normal to cry when you trip and get hurt
危ないから空中ブランコなんてしなくていいんだよ
The trapeze is dangerous, so you don't have to do it
「私がいなきゃ、誰がやるの！」とそう言って君は笑う
"If I don't, then who else will?" you say, laughing
危ないから綱渡りかなんしなくて欲しいんだよ
The tightrope is dangerous, so I'd really rather you didn't do it
でも、君には決めた事があるんでしょう？ 応援するよ
But I guess this is something you've decided on? I'll cheer you on
「頑張って！」
"Break a leg!"
実は僕は知っているよ 君が練習している事を 何回やってくってもたついいて
Actually, I know that even though you've practiced countless times, you still fumble
イライラしてしまう君の事を それだけやってれば上手くいくさ
Getting irritated, if you just keep at it, things will go well
そう、あやめ…そうそうそうように
That's right, Ayame... Like that, like that.
こちらですからね、あ、そうだった、そうだった、はい、いいよいいよ
It's right here, ah that's right, that's right, yep, okay!
いや、連勝シーカの方はね、あの、歌うパートでね、踊ってなかったりするのね
Well, for Renshou Seeker, you sometimes don't dance during the singing parts, right?
振りががあったりなかったり、そう、なかったりあるんですけど
Sometimes there's choreography, sometimes not—yeah, sometimes there is and sometimes there isn't.
お二人ともどうですか、先ほど見て、自信は終わりですか？
How about you two? Having seen that, are you feeling confident?
いや、ちょっとあの、そうね
Well, um... that's right.
振られれないように、ちゃんと動けないのがね
We have to make sure we don't get thrown off and can move properly...
あとね、場所がちょっとね、どうなるかっていう問題とかもあるからね
Also, there's the issue of positioning and how that'll turn out.
ほうずき、ゆえりの手、間違いがちこれ
Hozuki and Yueri's hands—people always mess that up!
え、と、これとかね、これとかこれとかね
Uh, like this one, or this one, or that one.
まあね、こちらは最後まで残った方に5ポイント入るらしいので、えっ？
Well, apparently the person who stays till the end gets 5 points, so—huh?
ちょっと大きいんじゃないですかポイントは、そう、そうなのよ
Isn't that a huge number of points? Yeah, exactly!
でも、うちも逆転するチャンスってこと？そう、そうなの！
Does that mean we have a chance for a comeback too? That's right!
これねバスクマ回避のためにぜひ頑張ってください
So please do your best to avoid being last place!
と言うことでやっていきましょうか
With that said, shall we get started?
え、でも何が来るかかんないんでしょ？何来るか分からないの、大丈夫ですか？
Wait, we don't know what's coming, right? Will we be okay not knowing?
最初はね、ちょっと確認しとくから。ほうずき、ゆえり来たら…
First, let's double-check. When Hozuki and Yueri come up...
回れ回れ！で、連勝シーカは…
Spin and spin! And for Renshou Seeker...
はい、じゃあどっちが掛かるか分からない状態で行きましょう！
Alright, let's go with a state where we don't know which one will play!
あ、まずは通常スピードでやってくれるそうなので、あ、はい、助かります。
Oh, they'll do it at normal speed first? Ah, great, that helps.
じゃ、それではミュージックスタート！
Well then, music start!
すれ違ってく
Passing each other by
街の灯り
The lights of the town
手を叩いて ほら 二人 見惚れて
Clapping our hands, look, the two of us are spellbound
終わりのない朝
A morning with no end
不意違い 踏み付けにはう
Clumsily stepping on each other—
それは
that's
ひらひら 踊れ 踊れ
fluttering, dance, dance!
秘密だいのとに 赤い果実に漬けた
A secret heartbeat, dipped in red fruit,
君に気付かれないように
so that you wouldn't notice.
おっと、二人とも大丈夫か？
Whoa, are you two okay?
じゃあ、リプレイ見てみましょうか！
Let's take a look at the replay!
すれ違ってく
Passing each other by
街の灯り
The lights of the town
手を叩いて ほら 二人 見惚れて
Clapping our hands, look, the two of us are spellbound
終わりのない朝
A morning with no end
不意違い 踏み付けにはう
Clumsily stepping on each other—
それは
that's
ひらひら 踊れ 踊れ
fluttering, dance, dance!
秘密だいのとに 赤い果実に漬けた
A secret heartbeat, dipped in red fruit,
君に気付かれないように
so that you wouldn't notice.
ちょっと待って、コメントも予算って、おかしいでしょ？
Wait, comments and budget? That's weird, right?
もう一回解きますか？これ上達的にはどうなんでしょうか？
Shall we do it again? How is our progress skill-wise?
え、なんとジャッジしていただけましょうか？
Um, how would you judge us?
あ、可愛い、可愛いコンビにして、あ、全員丸になってる！
Ah, make it a cute duo—oh, everyone got a circle!
全員丸、全員丸！やったー！
Everyone's a circle, everyone's a circle! Yay!
このままだと企画倒れになるから特別に丸にしてくれたそうですよ？
Apparently they made it a circle specially so the project wouldn't flop!
じゃあ、2回踊ってね、何とかよさも思い出すのではないでしょうか？
Well, by dancing twice, won't we remember the goodness of it?
じゃあ、連勝シーカも倍速でやっちゃいますか？
Shall we do Renshou Seeker at double speed too?
すれ違ってく
Passing each other by
街の灯り
The lights of the town
手を叩いて ほら 二人 見惚れて
Clapping our hands, look, the two of us are spellbound
終わりのない朝
A morning with no end
不意違い 踏み付けにはう
Clumsily stepping on each other—
それは
that's
ひらひら 踊れ 踊れ
fluttering, dance, dance!
心は 怒号の矢に その向こう願え踊る
My heart dances toward the arrow of shouting beyond it.
恋した時見へ 伝うように
As if conveying it to the moment I fell in love.
君に気付かれないように
So that you wouldn't notice.
これは…ちょっとちょっと間違っちゃった
Ah, wait, I made a bit of a mistake there.
てことで、これもリプレイ見てみましょう！
So let's watch the replay of this too!
高らかに 存在 証明 する んだ
Proclaiming our existence proudly,
誰かが 言う た ここ は 危険 な けもの道
Someone said this place is a dangerous animal trail,
ah 油断大敵 浮か れ て い たら
ah, letting your guard down means
オオカミ に 食べ られ てしまう よ
you'll end up being eaten by a wolf.
隠れて 様子見て そんな の つまらない
Hiding and watching is no fun at all,
今 こそ 本能 解放 サバンナ へ 急ごう
Now is the time to unleash our instincts, let's hurry to the savanna.
大気圏 の トレンド です
It's the trend of the atmosphere,
弱肉強食 は もう 古い
Survival of the fittest is already outdated.
楽しん だ もの 勝ち が 正義
The one who enjoys it wins, that's justice.
踊り 明かそう 願いこめ た エール ミライバルダンス
Let's dance the night away with an encouraging prayer: Miraival Dance.
これ、いろは間違えてると一見そう思いがちだけど
If you look at Iroha, you'd think she made a mistake,
何が正しいのかよくわかんない
but it's hard to tell what's actually correct.
よよよよ？
Yo-yo-yo-yo?
え、でも運営さんの判断を待ちましょう、これはね
Well, let's wait for management's judgment on this.
ど、どっちですかね？
Wh-Which is it?
あれ、よ、間違えちゃったかな？
Huh, yo, did I make a mistake?
どうでしたか？
How was it?
おー！丸だー！よかったー！
Oh! It's a circle! Yay!
でも確かにみんな違うふりのところもあったから分かりづらい
Everyone had different choreography, so it was hard to tell.
レディしかだけはね、絶対これも優しめ判定なはず
Lady Shika's part is definitely a generous judgment.
優しめ判定、優しい判定かな？
Generous judgment, a kind judgment?
企画通りになっちゃうからさ
Because it goes according to the plan.
確認はできましたね、ここからじゃあ本番でございます
We've confirmed it, now from here is the main round.
どっちの曲が流れるか分かりませんし、何倍かもわかんないよ
We don't know which song will play or how many times faster.
何倍もそうね、1.1倍からなのかな？
How many times, right? Is it from 1.1x?
順番で来るのかランダムなのか、それともランダムなのかね
Will it come in order or randomly, or is it totally random?
1.1からいっていくそうですよ、さっきのはちょっと早いですね
It goes up from 1.1x, the last one was a bit fast.
でもどっちが来るか分かりません、では１，２，３、おーけーです
We don't know which will come, alright, 1, 2, 3, okay.
お二人ともね、調子良さそうね。せーの、よーい、スタート！
Both of you seem to be in good shape. Ready, set, start!
高らかに 存在 証明 する んだ
Proclaiming our existence proudly,
誰かが 言う た ここ は 危険 な けもの道
Someone said this place is a dangerous animal trail,
ah 油断大敵 浮か れ て い たら
ah, letting your guard down means
オオカミ に 食べ られ てしまう よ
you'll end up being eaten by a wolf.
隠れて 様子見て そんな の つまらない
Hiding and watching is no fun at all,
今 こそ 本能 解放 サバンナ へ 急ごう
Now is the time to unleash our instincts, let's hurry to the savanna.
大気圏 の トレンド です
It's the trend of the atmosphere,
弱肉強食 は もう 古い
Survival of the fittest is already outdated.
楽しん だ もの 勝ち が 正義
The one who enjoys it wins, that's justice.
踊り 明かそう 願いこめ た エール ミライバルダンス
Let's dance the night away with an encouraging prayer: Miraival Dance.
いや、これちょっと、このテンマどうなっちゃうのこれ
Wait, what's going to happen with this tempo?!
これはまだでも1.1倍だからまだいけますよね？
Well, this is still 1.1x, so we can still manage, right?
ちょっと、ちょっと
Wait, wait.
でも1.1倍ですもんね。では、リプレイ、リプレイいきましょう
Well, it's 1.1x. Now let's check the replay.
高らかに 存在 証明 する んだ
Proclaiming our existence proudly,
誰かが 言う た ここ は 危険 な けもの道
Someone said this place is a dangerous animal trail,
ah 油断大敵 浮か れ て い たら
ah, letting your guard down means
オオカミ に 食べ られ てしまう よ
you'll end up being eaten by a wolf.
隠れて 様子見て そんな の つまらない
Hiding and watching is no fun at all,
今 こそ 本能 解放 サバンナ へ 急ごう
Now is the time to unleash our instincts, let's hurry to the savanna.
大気圏 の トレンド です
It's the trend of the atmosphere,
弱肉強食 は もう 古い
Survival of the fittest is already outdated.
楽しん だ もの 勝ち が 正義
The one who enjoys it wins, that's justice.
踊り 明かそう 願いこめ た エール ミライバルダンス
Let's dance the night away with an encouraging prayer: Miraival Dance.
合ってた！合ってた！みんな合ってた！
It was correct! Everyone was correct!
最初ね、最初ねちょっとどこ、ここいつもあれ？
At first, wait, at first, where is this always...
どうでしょうか？ジャッジは？
How was it? The judgment?
はい、判定は…丸だー！よかったー！
Yes, the judgment is... Circle! Yay!
しょうがないのよ、でもね。しょうがないの一言で片付けた
It can't be helped, though. Brushing it off with 'it can't be helped'.
どの程度のこりから、もうちょい真ん中の方がいいのかな？
From what point onwards should we be more in the middle?
要はあれですよ、フリーズ、こうやってやってるの、ソロパートですからね
In other words, doing freeze like this is because it's a solo part.
そう、そうそうそう。そろじゃないんです。え、でもそれを言ったら、もうみんなそう
Right, right. It's not solo. Well, if you say that, everyone's like that.
じゃあ、続いてまたスピードアップするそうなので、ちょっと頑張っていきましょうか
Well then, it seems speed will increase again next, so let's do our best.
高らかに 存在 証明 する んだ
Proclaiming our existence proudly,
誰かが 言う た ここ は 危険 な けもの道
Someone said this place is a dangerous animal trail,
ah 油断大敵 浮か れ て い たら
ah, letting your guard down means
オオカミ に 食べ られ てしまう よ
you'll end up being eaten by a wolf.
隠れて 様子見て そんな の つまらない
Hiding and watching is no fun at all,
今 こそ 本能 解放 サバンナ へ 急ごう
Now is the time to unleash our instincts, let's hurry to the savanna.
大気圏 の トレンド です
It's the trend of the atmosphere,
弱肉強食 は もう 古い
Survival of the fittest is already outdated.
楽しん だ もの 勝ち が 正義
The one who enjoys it wins, that's justice.
踊り 明かそう 願いこめ た エール ミライバルダンス
Let's dance the night away with an encouraging prayer: Miraival Dance.
え、これ1.1これね？わかんない、1.2だったのかな？
Wait, was this 1.1? I don't know, was it 1.2?
1.2だよね、1.2らしいです。ということでリプレイいきましょう
It's 1.2, apparently. So let's go to the replay.
早い！
Fast!
1.2でも早いかも
1.2 is pretty fast too.
どうだ？
How is it?
え、すごい。なんか早送りしてるみたいじゃん、さすがに
Whoa, amazing. It looks like it's fast-forwarded, seriously.
よく合ってる、よく合ってる
It matches well, it matches well.
あははは
Ahahaha.
え、どうだろ？あ、ちゃんと踊れてる？
Hm, how is it? Ah, am I dancing properly?
踊れてる、踊れてる！
I am, I am!
え、あやめさん、あやめさん、ちゃん、ちゃんとできてる？できてるもーん！
Hey, Ayame-san, are you doing it right? I totally am!
これ
This...
あ、でも、ま、でも、まぁまぁ踊れてるんじゃないですか？
Well, but, isn't this pretty decent?
できてる、できてる
We got it, we got it.
できてるのであれば、ここちょっと運営さんジャッジ
If we managed that, let's have management judge.
え、どうでしょう？どうでしょうか？結果は
Well, how is it? What's the result?
けっこ！
It's a tie!
おお、やった！やった！やった！
Oh, yay! Yay! Yay!
成功ということですね、これ
That means it's a success, right?
そういうことですね。成功だね。はあー、よかった！
That's right. Success! Phew, I'm glad!
いや本当に早くも出てたけど、次は1.2倍速
Man, that came out fast, but next is 1.2x speed.
おお、じゃあ次は1.3が来る？
Oh, so next is 1.3x?
ええ？ええー？
What?!
お疲れなんですけど...
We're already exhausted...
大丈夫ですか？息切れだけで大丈夫ね。
Are you okay? Just out of breath, we'll be fine.
続いていきましょうか。
Shall we keep going?
オッケー！
Okay!
はい、じゃあ続いてのミュージック、スタート！どっちだ？
Alright, next music, start! Which one is it?
DANCE! 自在のステップトゥーステップだって
DANCE! Freestyle steps, even two steps,
プログラムの範疇さ
Are within the realm of the program.
YOU! 呼吸を乱している？
YOU! Is your breathing disrupted?
なんて非効率的でしょう
How inefficient that is.
ロボットダンス
Robot dance.
LOCK! 交わしてアイートアイ
LOCK! Intersecting eye to eye,
すでに次元も超えた戦いだ
It's already a battle beyond dimensions.
アイ
EYE
思考を乱している
Disrupting my thoughts,
胸が高鳴っていく
My heart is pounding.
インプット
Input.
UP SIDE UP SIDE DOWN
UP SIDE DOWN SIDE UP AND DOWN
LEFT SIDE
LEFT SIDE RIGHT LEFT RIGHT UP DOWN
YOU AND ME
ときめく心のエモーションが
The throbbing emotional heart,
あなたに共鳴して止まらないのだ！
Resonates with you and won't stop!
合成とは真逆のプログラム
A program opposite to synthesis,
知りたい 知りたい
I want to know, I want to know,
ねえもっと付き合って！
Hey, spend more time with me!
ダンスロボットダンス もーいいかい？
Dance robot dance, are you ready?
ダンスロボットダンス まーだだよ
Dance robot dance, not yet.
いや、やば...
Man, that was...
息切れてく
I'm running out of breath.
やばい！
Yikes!
はやーい！はやすぎたし
So fast! Way too fast.
まさ、でも、まあ、まだ踊れてるじゃないですか
Well, but, aren't we still dancing though?
できてる、できてる！できてるの？
We got it! Did we really?
できてるのであれば、ここちょっと運営さんジャッジ
If we managed, management judge this part.
え、どうでしょう？
Well, how is it?
どうでしょうか？
What do you think?
結果！
Result!
おおっ！
Oh!
あ、やった！やった！
Ah, yay! Yay!
よかった！
Awesome!
やった！成功ということですね、これ
Yay! That means it's a success, right?
そういうことですね。成功だね。
That's right. Success.
はあ、はやい、はやい！
Phew, so fast!
でも、いーちゃんは通ってた
Even so, Ii-chan passed.
そうだね、よかったね。
That's true, good for you.
これできなかった
I couldn't do this part.
どういうことですね
What does that mean...
じゃあ次は
So next is...
判定はいかほど
Let's see the judgment.
ええっ！？うそでしょ！？
What?! No way?!
うそでしょ！？えっ！？
No way?! Eh?!
うそでしょ！？がんばってたのに！
No way?! Even though we tried our best!
まじか...
Seriously...
マジで！？いや、白髪の勝ちで...
Seriously?! Wait, Shirakami wins...
いいんですか白髪の勝ちで？
Is it okay for Shirakami to win?
いやいや、ちょっと待ってくださいよ。
No no, wait a second.
待ってくださいよ。どうされました？
Hold on. What happened?
すみません。
Excuse me.
ちょっと...
Um...
あれはちょっと、申し訳ございません。
About that, I am so sorry.
ねえ、なんでしょうか？
Hey, what is it?
ちょっともう1回お願いしても... いいでしょうか？
Could you let us try one more time... please?
お願いします。
Please.
よろしくお願いします。
Please do us this favor.
Please, please.
そうですね。うん。
I see. Yeah.
これはどうかっ... 水の底にも聞いてみましょうかねえ。
I wonder... Let's ask the bottom of the water too.
ちょっとカメラさん近づいてもらってじゃあ、みんなに...
Camera-san, come closer, and let's ask everyone...
みなさん、どうなんですか？やらせてあげてもいいかな？お願い。いいよって言ってくれますかね？
Everyone, what do you think? Should we let them do it again? Please. Will you say 'okay'?
「くさ」って言われてますけど
Though they're calling us 'cringe'.
もう1回！
One more time!
丸ほしいな。がんばったんだよ！丸ほしい！
I want a circle. We tried so hard! We want a circle!
もういいかげんもう1回オッケーだって！オッケー！ええ、やったあ！
Alright, one more time is okay! Okay! Yay!
もう1回でやりましょうか。
Shall we do it one more time?
よしよしよしよし... チャンスがあれば、ねえ。チャンスがあるというなら、もう1回やりますわ。
Alright alright... If we have a chance, right. If there's a chance, we'll do it again.
でもさっきより早いですからね。ええ？
But it'll be faster than before, you know. Eh?
でもそれは、あれですよね？フブキちゃんも... もちろん！もちろん！
But that applies to Fubuki-chan too, right? Of course! Of course!
ディスコがかかっているという。ということで、1.4倍速だそうです、次。やべえ！
Disco music is playing. So next is 1.4x speed. Oh crap!
どっちの曲が来るかわかんないですかね？はい。いきますよじゃあ。ミュージックスタート！
Wonder which song will come up? Right. Let's go then. Music start!
DANCE! 自在のステップトゥーステップだって
DANCE! Freestyle steps, even two steps,
プログラムの範疇さ
Are within the realm of the program.
YOU! 呼吸を乱している？
YOU! Is your breathing disrupted?
なんて非効率的でしょう
How inefficient that is.
ロボットダンス
Robot dance.
LOCK! 交わしてアイートアイ
LOCK! Intersecting eye to eye,
すでに次元も超えた戦いだ
It's already a battle beyond dimensions.
アイ
EYE
思考を乱している
Disrupting my thoughts,
胸が高鳴っていく
My heart is pounding.
インプット
Input.
UP SIDE UP SIDE DOWN
UP SIDE DOWN SIDE UP AND DOWN
LEFT SIDE
LEFT SIDE RIGHT LEFT RIGHT UP DOWN
YOU AND ME
ときめく心のエモーションが
The throbbing emotional heart,
あなたに共鳴して止まらないのだ！
Resonates with you and won't stop!
合成とは真逆のプログラム
A program opposite to synthesis,
知りたい 知りたい
I want to know, I want to know,
ねえもっと付き合って！
Hey, spend more time with me!
ダンスロボットダンス もーいいかい？
Dance robot dance, are you ready?
ダンスロボットダンス まーだだよ
Dance robot dance, not yet.
いや、がんばったと思う。
Man, I think we did our best.
どうだ？
How was it?
いや、まあ、そろそろついてくる
Well, we're finally keeping up.
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
ついていくのにやっとこさよ！
It was all we could do to keep up!
なんだこれ...
What is this...
はやすぎだよ！
Way too fast!
まあまあ、一回オッケーだって！オッケー！
Well, one time is okay! Okay!
じゃあではでは改めてまして、上さんの結果、どうでしょうか？おねがい！
Well then, once again, what are Ue-san's results? Please!
おおーー！やったーー！うれしい！
Oooh! Yay! I'm so happy!
いや、1.4倍速の練習試合成り立ったの余裕じゃないですかちょっと！
Wait, doing a 1.4x speed practice match effortlessly like that!
おいといけちゃいましたねー
We pulled it off easily, huh?
ねー
Yeah.
いや、これ問題は鬼頭木日和ですよ
Well, the problem here is "Houzuki Biyori."
来るか分からないですけどね
Though we don't know if it'll show up.
鬼頭木日和が1.5倍きちゃったらやばいよ
If "Houzuki Biyori" comes at 1.5x speed, that'd be terrible!
いや、かわいいな
Man, that's adorable.
ということでじゃあ
So with that said,
続いて1.5倍！
moving on to 1.5x speed!
さあどの曲が来るか、どっちが来るか、その想像マジで
Now, which song is coming? Which one will it be? I honestly can't even imagine!
はい、じゃあ行きましょう
Alright, let's go!
準備いいですか？
Are you ready?
はい
Yes.
はい行きますよ、ミュージックスタート！
Alright, here we go. Music, start!
間違った！
I messed up!
足が！足が！
My feet! My feet!
ちょっとここ流れ
Wait, the flow here...
ほら間違っちゃったもう
See, I already messed up!
で、戻りましょう
Let's go back...
リプレイ行きましょうか！リプレイ！
Shall we go to the replay? Replay!
こちらです！間違っちゃった！
Here it is! I messed up!
さあどうだ？
Now, how was it?
がんばれがんばれ
Do your best!
足が！足が！ちょっとちょっとびょんって
My feet! My feet! Wait, it just bopped...
いやこれは完璧なるミス
Man, this is a total mistake.
さてじゃあ
So then,
えのきさんの結果いってみましょう！えのきさん結果はこちら！
let's check Enoki-san's results! Enoki-san's results are right here!
おー！
Oh!
早すぎただけ
Just too fast—
ざまあみろですわ！
Serves you right!
チクショー！
Damn it!
いやでもこれはお目文字、スガスガしく間違えてますね
Well, but this is overtly, refreshingly mistaken.
そうですね、すげえいい勝負だったぞ
That's right, it was a really good match.
これ難しかったね
This was difficult, huh?
いや、これね、ほら、足がね、ビヨビヨビヨビヨになるんですよ
Yeah, this, look, the legs go all bouncy like that.
いやこれ
Man, this—
これやばかったね
This was crazy.
足りすぎた
Too much leg.
ま、ということで、なんか2人残っちゃったらしいので、じゃあ脱落です。
Well, with that said, since two people apparently remained, they're eliminated.
え？ということは、Mio-san脱落ということでお休みをいただきまして、私とMioで...え？
Eh? That means Mio-san is eliminated and taking a break, and me and Mio... eh?
最終決戦をする？おー、頂上決戦！
Have a final showdown? Oh, a summit clash!
ということで、どこで見取ったらええかしら？
So where should I watch from, I wonder?
じゃあ、私とMioで、じゃあ最後の...最後の決戦だ。
Then, me and Mio, for the final... final showdown.
最後は、あと1.5倍速ですかね、これもしやすると。
The last one is probably 1.5x speed, if I had to guess.
じゃあ行きますか。倍速は分かりませんが、じゃあ行きましょう！やってみよう！
Shall we go? We don't know the speed, but let's go! Let's try it!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
はやっ！ついていけない！
So fast! I can't keep up!
負けたかも知れない！リプレイよ、お願い！
I might have lost! Replay, please!
最後やっちゃったかも。
I might have messed up at the end.
おお、これは！結構接戦じゃないですか？
Oh, wow! Isn't this quite a close match?
ということで、じゃあうえさん結果見ていきましょう。
So, let's check Ues-an's results.
あ、もうちょっと待ってくださいね、うえさん結果。え、でも結構接戦だったんじゃないですか？
Ah, wait just a moment, Ues-an's results. Eh, but wasn't it a pretty close match?
あ、足が違っちゃった！
Ah, my feet got mixed up!
今までのせっきてきたフブキちゃんは...どうなんだ？結構アヤウイちゃん...一番さいかいですからね、今撮ってんの。
Up until now, Fubuki-chan who's been accumulating... how is it? Quite Ayaui-chan... she's in last place right now.
じゃあ、うえさんの結果こちら！
Now, Ues-an's results are right here!
いえーーい！
Yay!
わざわざ何よのってさ！
What do you mean "What's that"!
何の感動もなくだから悔しくていいよ！
No emotion at all, so I'm frustrated!
ほうずきびよりなら勝てたのにさ！
If it was Houzuki Biyori, I would have won!
ほうずきびよりの2倍速なら勝てたのにさ！おめでとみオちゃん！
If it was 2x Houzuki Biyori, I would have won! Congratulations, Mio-chan!
まさかの逆転かもしれない。
Could be an unexpected comeback.
と言うことでね、どうなんでしょう。
So, I wonder how it is.
今回ほんとあれだね、鬼来なくてもよかったね。
This time really, you didn't even need Oni to show up.
と言うことでじゃあ結果来ましたので、最終結果こちらです！
With that said, the results are in, so here is the final result!
みお7、あやめ3、...
Mio 7, Ayame 3...
とうとうということで、
So, finally...
やった！逆転勝利だー！
Yay! A comeback victory!
え、罰ゲームは、お、あやめちゃんに決定！
Huh, the penalty game is decided for Ayame-chan!
あれ、今帰ろうとしてませんでした？
Huh, weren't you trying to go home just now?
いや、今日のとこはちょっと、ねえ、早く帰らせて
No, as for today, just let me go home early...
いや、帰らせませんよ！しゅうしゅうしゅうしゅう！
No, we won't let you go home! Gather, gather!
いやです！おねがいします！やめてください！
No way! Please! Stop it!
とうとうということで、罰ゲームは！
So, finally, the penalty game is!
なりきり歌詞朗読！
Roleplay lyrics recitation!
なにそれ、なりきり歌詞朗読ってなんだ？
What's that? What's "roleplay lyrics recitation"?
あやめちゃんにはですね、お題ボックスからなりきりお題と歌詞を引いてもらいます！
Ayame-chan will draw a roleplay prompt and lyrics!
お題になりきって歌詞を朗読してもらう地獄企画となっておりますよ！
Recite the lyrics while acting out the prompt!
やだなぁ！これ終わったら稼いだギャラを返して！
No way! When this is over, give back my earnings!
ということで、お題ボックスお願いします！
So, please bring out the prompt box!
ちょっとちょっと待ってくださいよ！
Wait, wait a minute!
泣き寝入りじゃなくて？そういうことだ！
Not crying yourself to sleep? So that's how it is!
ではまずお題ボックスから引いていただきましょうか。
Now, let's have you draw from the prompt box.
はい、じゃあこっちを。はい、1枚引いてください。
Right, then this one. Please draw one.
たのむたのむ、ちょっと地獄じゃないお題お願いします。
I beg you for a prompt that isn't hellish.
さあ、お題は何？
Now, what's the prompt?
お願いします、先に、お題をじゃあ発表してもらいましょうか。
Let's have you announce the prompt first!
ええと、なんだ？侍！じゃあ侍になりきって
Uh, what is it? Samurai! So, acting like a samurai...
なりきって、じゃあ次歌詞ボックスから、じゃあ歌詞を読みましょう。
Next, let's read the lyrics from the lyric box.
侍になりきって歌詞を読むってどういうことなんだ？
What does it mean to read lyrics like a samurai?
えい！じゃあちょっと開けさせていただきますよ。
Here goes! Then I'll open it up.
これ、これ歌詞ですね？どこの歌詞が来るかはちょっとわかんないね。
We don't know which lyrics will come out.
もしかしたらサムライっぽい歌詞が来るかもしれないから。
It might be samurai-esque lyrics.
お、えでも、「願いばいつかは晴れよと闇に隠せし恋心」...
"If I pray for the skies to clear someday..."
え、これちょっと恋愛シカで合ってるんじゃないですか？
Wait, isn't this fitting for a romantic scenario?
いいですね、いい感じに。サムライを意識してやってください。
That's good. Do it with a samurai mindset.
いやそんな簡単じゃ、そんな簡単じゃないでしょ！ちゃんとね、心までサムライになりきってないよ。
You haven't fully embodied a samurai yet!
そう、泣きりサムライだ、泣きりサムライ。頼むで！
Right, Nakiri Samurai. I'm counting on you!
じゃあちょっとお題ボックスよけていただきましょうか。
Could you please move the prompt box aside?
さようならお題ボックス。いやこれちょっと結構難しいですよ。
Goodbye, prompt box. This is pretty difficult.
これね、どうしようかな、これ。さあ、じゃあ武士、はい。
What should I do? A samurai, yes.
じゃあよろしいですか？
Are you ready?
それでは、じゃああやめちゃんのサムライになりきっての歌詞まで、3、2、1どうぞ！
Starting Ayame-chan's samurai recitation in 3, 2, 1!
願いばいつかは晴れよと闇に隠せし恋心、雲の隙間に光り差す、今この時に
Hidden in the darkness is my romantic heart...
なんかちょっと平安時代を感じる。
Somehow it feels like the Heian period.
え、いいじゃん、だめ？うえしゃきオッケー？
Isn't it good? Ueshaki okay?
うえしゃきオッケー？どうですか、うえしゃきオッケー？
How is it, Ueshaki okay?
よかったね！気宇深かったよね。
That was great! It had deep emotion.
よかったね！ということで、いろはにダンスチャレンジでした！
So, that was Irohani Dance Challenge!
さてさて、ということでここまで色々やってきたんでございますけどもお待たせいたしました！
We've done a lot, but thank you for waiting!
皆さんから募集した単価のグランプリの発表のお時間がやってまいりました！
The time has come to announce the Grand Prix!
ついに5000通の中から選りすぐったもさんの
From among 5,000 entries selected by Mo-san...
本当にたくさん応募ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for all the submissions!
今回は我々3人が選んだふぶき賞、あやめ賞、みお賞の順で発表していこうと思います。
We'll announce the Fubuki, Ayame, and Mio awards.
それではまずふぶき賞から発表したいと思います！ふぶき賞に選ばれたのはこちら！
First, the Fubuki Award! Here it is!
あなたとね、食べるご飯が、大好きです。もっちゃもっちゃ、きつねのうどん
Eating meals with you is what I love most. Nom-nom-nom, kitsune udon.
はーい！それではだんちょーさんのこちらをふぶき賞とさせていただきます！
Ha-i! So we'll make Danchou-san's entry the Fubuki Award!
いやこれなんかあなたとねがすごい好き。食べる感じが。あなたとから始まるのがなんか、白神らしいなって感じがして。
I really love this "with you" part. It feels so Shirakami-like.
あなたとね 食べるご飯が 大好きです もっちゃもっちゃ、きつねうどん
My absolute favorite thing is eating kitsune udon with you!
ハンド＆ホーム だいちゃーい。
Han-doru & home, da-ich-ii...
はい、じゃあ続いてはあやめ賞行きましょうかね。
And now, let's go to Ayame's turn!
はい、じゃああやめ賞もお願いします。
Ayame's turn, please!
やっべえよ、なんにもきいてなかったよ
Yabeee, yo! I didn't listen to anything, yo!
せっせっせーの、なややよーで！
Sensei-sei-no, na-ya-ya-yo-de!
いや、これはあの実によくよー表してくれている曲ではないでしょうかね？
Well, this isn't really showing Ayame very well, is it?
よね。
Yora ne.
と思ってね、こちら表現していただきました。ありがとうございます！
So you thought this expressed Ayame? Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん！
Pyon pyon pyon pyon pyon pyon pyon!
はい、じゃあ続いてみお賞！
All right, next is Mio's turn!
おっ、みお賞です。
It's Mio's turn.
はい、こちら！
Here it is!
くしゃみの音（ね） 可憐な悲鳴 不意のPON（ポン）
The sound of a sneeze (ne), a lovely tragic princess, a "pon" sneeze (pon),
ミオファの森も いとさんざめく
and even Miofa's forest echoes warmly.
こちらにさせていただきました！
I was allowed to do this one!
いいですね！
Nice!
はい、おめでとうございます！
Thank you so much!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
なんか一緒に放送楽しんでる感じがしてて、すごくよかったなって思って。
It felt like we were all enjoying the broadcast together, and I thought it was really nice.
そうそう、くしゃみに歓喜してるみおファね。
Right, Miofa sneezing and going "pon,"
ホラーでね、あのうちはぎゃあぎゃあ言ってるのみんな喜んでたりとかね。
and everyone being happy when we're going wild in horror,
うちがポーンしてるのみんな喜んでたりね、みんな喜んでね。
and everyone being happy when I'm pon. Everybody's happy, right?
なんかざめいて、みおファの森を表現してくれて、ざめんだよね。
And it really captured Miofa's forest wonderfully, didn't it?
というわけで、
And that's it!
以上ですね、タンカルグランプリ発表でございました！
That concludes the Tanukaro Grand Prix announcement!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
しかし、こちらですね、ただただ選ばせていただいただけではございません。
However, we didn't just get to choose them, did we?
なんだって？
What do you mean?
なんと選ばれた、えーこちらの3つの短歌を使って
What? We've chosen three tanka to create...
グッズを作成させていただきます！グッズ！グッズです！
goods! We are going to make goods!
えっ、どういうこと？グッズ？
Wait, what kind of goods?
はい、詳細などはね、追って発表しますので、皆さんも楽しみに！
Well, we'll announce the details later, so everyone look forward to it!
いえーい！チェックチェック！
Yay! Check it out!
てことは、あやふぶみグッズが出 るってこと？
Does that mean Ayahubumi goods will be released?
そうゆうこと！選ばれた短歌の方、改めておめでとうございます！
That's right! Everyone whose tanka was chosen, congratulations once again!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
さてさて、お届けしてきました恋情詩歌リリース記念なま放送ですが、そろそろね、お別れのお時間がやってまいりました！
Now then, we've brought you this: the release celebration stream for "Kaishin no Ichigeki!" But the time for parting is almost here.
あー、もうそんな時間、1時間だったね！ね！
Ah, it really was just one hour, wasn't it?
はい、いや、どうでしたか今回あやめちゃん、どうでしたか？おねがいします。
Yeah. So, how was it, Ayame-chan, how was it?
いや、ちょっとダンスけっこういけるんじゃないかと思いましたけど、
Well, I thought I could pull off dancing pretty well,
まあ、あの、いい結果だったと…。
well, you know... I guess it was a good result.
おもんな、おもんな。楽しかったでーす。ありがとうございました！
It was fun! Thank you very much!
いえーい！やったづいてみよう。
Let's keep dancing!
はい。えっと、ダンスで、えっと最後まで残れたのはすごいね、
And for the dancing part,
あのあやめと二人ででした。土下座のおかげだったと思います。
that was thanks to Ayame, I think, and being on our knees.
あ、そうそう！じゃみおちゃグランプリ取れたのもよ、一緒ってことだよね？
That's right! So even though we both got the Tanuki Grand Prix, we were in it together!
ね？
Right?
違うみたいよ？
Wait, different meaning?
それはってこと？
What does that mean?
まあまあ、あの、いい、いい癒やしができたなって思います。
Well, you know, I think it gave us some peace of mind.
そうですね！はい、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, thank you very much!
というわけでね、こうやってね、なんかいろいろ遊んだりとかできたのですごい、楽しかったです！
So having fun playing around like this with Ayahubumi was really a lot of fun.
楽しかったね！
It was fun!
はい、いやまたなんかダンスやるかい？
Yes! And maybe we should do some more dancing?
もう？でも総合的には白上っちが一番よかったぞ！
Well, overall, Shirakami did the best, though!
あれ？
What?
言えよ！うちが優勝したんだからうちがよかったに決まってるじゃないですか！
I mean, since I won the tournament, it's pretty much decided that I was the best, right?
いや待って、慈悲のないナキリでしょ！
That's just called no mercy!
ナキリでしょ！ナキリでしょ！
No mercy!
まあ、みんなよかったってことでしょう！みんなよかったってことですね。
So that means everyone did great, right?
よかった、みんなよかった。配信はあやふぶにコラボで。
Everyone did great! And this broadcast is all thanks to Ayahubumi collab.
あ、そしたら誰が一番よかったかね。ぜひぜひ「武士道ナキリ」でよろしくお願いします。
Now, between the two of us, who did best? Let's hear it: "Bushido Nakiri," please treat us well!
がんばってたよー！
She was trying her best, you know?
みんなほら、よかった、よかった。武士道ナキリよかったって！
So everyone was like, "It was good! Bushido Nakiri was good!"
よかったよ！みんなよかったよ！
It was good! Everyone was good!
っていうことでね、今日はみなさん本当にかっこありがとうございました！
So, thank you all so much for today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
引き続いてあやふぶにほえっとあやふぶみを！せーの！よろしくおねがいしまーす！
Let's do the final Ayahubumi Ayafubumi together, ready, go!
たーすー！
Hooray!
それではみなさん、えっ、次は不二から、不二やの…
And everyone, next is Fubuki's...
あ、不二やの！誕生日！
Fubuya's birthday!
なんとね、なんかゲンコにヨガがいるそうな。
Apparently, Genko is going to have yoga!
えっ？いましお！
What? It's mashio!
じゃあ引き続きお楽しみに！
So, look forward to that too!
お楽しみに！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!